# HIGUERA HAROL

Aichi-ken Nagoya-shi Nakamura-ku 4-50 Taiko Tori, 504 Mansion Nakamura, 453-0811

Mobile: 070-1744-2311 harolhiguera2005@gmail.com

#### CAREER OVERVIEW

Talented, honest and quick learner with solid theoretical and practical academic background in Electronics and Software Engineering, experienced in control design, analogue Electronic design, embedded systems, Android applications development and web programming languages, object oriented programming and scripting languages.

#### **CORE STRENGTHS**

- Electronic Engineering
- Fast Learner
- Programming and Design Skills
- Theoretical and practical engineering
- Creative
- General Math
- Open minded to multidisciplinary fields of engineering
- Good attention to detail and design
- · Deadline-oriented
- Committed
- Strong problem solving skills

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- Electronic Circuit Design: Experience in embedded systems development, including control design, circuit design, PCB development, FPGA and microprocessor architecture, UML, DRBFM, components selection and purchasing. Ability and experience in Kicad and Orcad Suite products for simulation and PCB design purposes.
- Android Application Development: Native development knowledge and experience for Android Devices. Ability to work with IDEs such as Eclipse and Android Studio. Programming Languages: Java, php, SQL and XML.
- Web Development: Experience and knowledge in various programming languages for front and back end development as well as database implementation when is required: JavaScript, php, HTML, CSS, AJAX, MySQL, JQuery and JSON.
- Other software Skills: Matlab, Simulink, Labview, Illustrator, Photoshop, Ms Excel, Ms Word, Ms PowerPoint.

# RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

04/2015 to 09/2015 Electronic Engineer, Control design

**ASAHI VISION**, Nagoya, Aichi, Japan

Product development engineer, In charge of control design for ophthalmic equipment, algorithms, and simulations. Software tools: Matlab, Visual studio, UML.

10/2013 to 3/2015 Electronic Engineer, Android Developer

ROBOTAPP - Bucaramanga, Colombia

Entrepreneur-Co founder. Analogue design of the control and electronic systems for a Robot. Implementation of the wireless communication. Programming of micro-controllers. PCB's circuit

boards design. Development of an Android application to interact with the robot remotely. Software tools: Eclipse, Illustrator, Kicad.

12/2012 to 04/2013 Lecturer

TEMPORARY UNION "CETICS", PROGRAM APPS.CO. MINISTRY OF

TELECOMMUNICATIONS - Bucaramanga, Colombia

Served as an Android lecturer and technical adviser at a program

for Entrepreneurs led by a government.

# **ADDITIONAL EXPERIENCE**

07/2014 to 07/2014 Freelancer, Web developer

**TSUNAGO** – Tokyo, Japan

Responsive Front End development based on PSD design for Marketing Purposes. Technology used: HTML, CSS, CSS Media

Queries, JavaScript, Photoshop.

02/2014 to 03/2014 Freelancer, Android Application developer

Uts.edu.co – Bucaramanga, Colombia

Development of an Android application that allows students to register subjects in an Educational Institution. Technologies used: Eclipse, NotePad++, SQL, Java, Php, PostgreSQL, XML and JSON.

# **EDUCATION**

12/2013 Bachelor of Science: Electronic Engineering and

telecommunication systems.

INDUSTRIAL UNIVERSITY OF SANTANDER (UIS) - Bucaramanga,

Colombia.

2005-2008, 2011-2013

10/2012 Seminar Course: Android Systems and Geolocation Principles.

RADIOGIS, TELECOMMUNICATIONS RESEARCHING GROUP, UIS -

Bucaramanga, Colombia

10/2011 Language Studies: English and Business

**PRINCESS COLLEGE** – London, United Kingdom.

Level: Fluent.

03/2014 to 03/2015 Language Studies: Japanese language

KYOTO INTERNATIONAL COMMUNITY HOUSE – Kyoto, Japan. Level: Intermediate Conversational, able to read and write in

Hiragana and Katakana.

# **ADDITIONAL TRAINING**

11/2012 Training Course: Rotating Electric Machines (DC and AC

Motors)

NATIONAL LEARNING SERVICE - Medellin, Colombia.

Duration: 40 Hours.

10/2012 Training Course: Electronic product design with

microcontrollers.

NATIONAL LEARNING SERVICE - Cali, Colombia.

Duration: 40 Hours.